MICHAEL A SCHIENBEIN

▼ ma@schienbe.in

schienbe.in

+12064749712 in michael-schienbein

mschien

SUMMARY

Software engineer pivoting from over 10 years as a professional Stage Technician. Excellent Leadership Skills and ability to handle unpredictability from years of working in a fast paced environment. Comfortable Leading teams and working with diverse groups of all sizes. Authorized to work in the USA.

SKILLS

Full-Stack Web Dev: Python, Flask, Javascript, ¡Query, ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Jinja, Bulma, Bootstrap

QA: Jasmin, Jest, Unittest, Supertest

Database Management: SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLAlchemy

Other Languages / Tools: Git, Github, Shell, Regex

Operating Systems: Unix, Windows, Linux

WORK EXPERIENCE

Keymix - Intelligent Spotify recommendation engine - Project

Feb. 2021 - Mar. 2021

- Main Technologies: Python, Flask, JQuery, Axios, SQLAlchemy, Postgres, HTML5, CSS, Bulma.

Seattle Symphony Orchestra - Stage Technician - Seattle, WA

Feb. 2010 - Dec. 2018

- Worked closely with 70 Seattle Symphony musicians to produce over 300 live shows per season.
- Stage managed live events with 50-200+ performers and crew members.
- Worked with cutting edge professional lighting/audio/video software.

City of Seattle - Intermittent Stage Technician - Seattle, WA

Aug. 2008 - July 2012

- Handled a rich array of client requests to produce over 400 live events in 4 years.
- Regularly lead crews of 20+ members.
- Involved in the solving the technical challenges of 100 stadium concerts, 20 trade shows, and 10 conferences yearly.

EDUCATION

Springboard Software Engineering Career Track, Certification

Oct. 2020 - Current

- 700+ Hour intensive course in Software Engineering methodologies and technologies.
- Covers key aspects of front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, and data structures and algorithms.
- Web Development, JavaScript, DOM Manipulation, Event Driven Programming, Git/Terminal/Github, Modern JavaScript and Testing, AJAX, jQuery, ReactJS, Redux, SQL, PostgresQL, Flask, Node, Express, Data Structures and Algorithms.